Air Force leadership from around the Pacific convened at Yokota
Air Base for a safety-board president course intended to
prepare them should they ever need to serve as a
board president on a mishap investigation board.
The course prepares members to serve on a safety investigation
board designed to prevent future mishaps, where information is confidential,
or on an accident investigation board, where the findings will
be released to the public.
It does provide clarity into the situation, and we
want to make sure we have the best-trained personnel
who are going to be doing these investigations,
primarily because we want to get the best answer to the
next of kin in explaining what happened to their loved
one in the final moments.
And we also need that transparency of government to explain
what happened to an aircraft or an operational asset if
they are destroyed.
After completing the course, the students will be familiar with
the process of both types of boards and how to
effectively manage them.
Petty Officer Phil Stewart, Yokota Air Base, Japan.